Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids: Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：是的，是的，队长。
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:   Aye, aye,
Captain!
孩子们：是啊是啊
队长！
Captain: ♪ Ohh... ♪
队长：♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Man: We take you now to
Encino, California.
男：我们现在带你去
加利福尼亚州恩西诺。
Where we find the president of
the SpongeBob
SquarePants fan club...
我们在哪里找到总统
海绵宝宝
方裤粉丝俱乐部...
Flipping burgers?
翻转汉堡？
Oh, hey, kids.
哦，嘿，孩子们。
Potty and I took jobs flipping
burgers so we can be just like
our hero
波蒂和我的工作翻转
汉堡，这样我们就可以像
我们的英雄
SpongeBob SquarePants.
海绵宝宝。
I took the job for
the free sodas.
我接受这份工作是为了
免费的苏打水。
Potty, don't you
have dishes to wash?
便盆，你不是吗
有碗要洗吗？
Argh...
啊啊……
Ooh, hey, kids, say hello
to my boss, Mr. Pirateson.
哦，嘿，孩子们，打个招呼
给我的老板，海盗先生。
Argh...
啊啊……
One order of scurvy fries,
one large bilge water.
一份坏血病薯条，
一大堆舱底水。
Argh...
啊啊……
Diet bilge water.
饮食舱底水。
Argh...
啊啊……
I'll get right on it, sir.
我会马上处理的，先生。
Ah...
啊...
P.U., what died in here?
P.U.，这里死了什么？
Oh, Potty, you're just in time
to try me new Pirate Patties.
哦，波蒂，你来得正是时候
来尝尝我新推出的海盗馅饼。
I call this one
我称这个为
"Buried Treasure".
“埋藏的宝藏”。
Where'd you dig that one up?
你在哪里挖到这个的？
This one's called
这个叫
"Walk the Plank".
“走木板”。
I'm already "bored"
with that one.
我已经“无聊”了
与那个。
This one will blow that little
bird brain of yours.
这个会吹那么一点
你的鸟脑。
Behold, the Patchy Patty.
看哪，帕奇·帕蒂。
Ahoy.
哎呀。
Oh, that's the worst
one yet  .
哦，这是最糟糕的
还没有一个。
Potty Parrot, you are never
supportive of me.
便盆鹦鹉，你从来都不是
支持我。
: I don't wanna
be your friend anymore.
: 我不想
不再是你的朋友了。
: I never wanna
see you again.
: 我从来不想
再见。
Patchy, no.
补丁，不。
You know, this isn't the first
time that a Patty has come
between two good chums.
你知道，这不是第一次
帕蒂来的时间
两个好朋友之间。
It happened once
in Bikini Bottom.
发生过一次
在比基尼底部。
Here, take a look while
I pull myself together.
来来来，一会儿看一下
我振作起来。
Hmm, something ain't right.
嗯，有些不对劲。
For me?
为我？
Don't you find this
a tad suspicious?
你没发现这个吗
有点可疑？
Suspicion doesn't old a candle
to birthday wishing.
怀疑不会使蜡烛变老
到生日愿望。
Surprise!
惊喜！
Duck!
鸭子！
Disengage.
脱离。
Mr. Krabs: Me secret formula!
蟹老板：我的秘密配方！
Plankton: Happy birthday, Krabs!
浮游生物：生日快乐，蟹蟹！
Don't forget your
condiments, Plankton.
别忘了你的
调味品，浮游生物。
That a boy, SpongeBob.
那是一个男孩，海绵宝宝。
Safe!
安全的！
You'll rue the day
we were born, Krabs.
你会后悔这一天
我们诞生了，蟹蟹。
I'll be back.
我会回来的。
Oh, barnacle.
哦，藤壶。
All:
全部：
Why, Mr. Krabs?
为什么，蟹老板？
Why does he hate us so?
他为什么这么恨我们？
Well, you might as well
blame me, SpongeBob.
嗯，你也可以
怪我吧，海绵宝宝。
There was a time when
Plankton and I were...
曾经有一段时间
浮游生物和我...
Best friends.
最好的朋友。
Best friends?
最好的朋友？
Friends at birth,
you might say.
出生时的朋友，
你可能会说。
Even as wee ones...
即使是小孩子...
Goo.
粘性物。
Voices: Aw...
声音：啊……
Mr. Krabs: Things were all
peaches and cream.
蟹老板：一切都过去了
桃子和奶油。
Voices: Aw...
声音：啊……
Mr. Krabs: Until we hit
grade school.
蟹老板：直到我们击中
小学。
Hey, Planky, what you doing?
嘿，普朗基，你在做什么？
Oh, just a little something I
thought I'd try out.
哦，只是一点点我
我想我会尝试一下。
Kids:
孩子们：
Idiots!
白痴！
I'll show you with science!
我用科学告诉你！
This concoction's gonna blow
everyone away.
这混合物会爆炸
大家都走开。
Kids:
孩子们：
how's this for a science
experiment, Mr.
Brain-A-Tron 5000?
这是一门科学吗？
实验，先生
Brain-A-Tron 5000？
Oh, they'll pay for
this one day, Eugene.
哦，他们会付出代价的
这一天，尤金。
Darn tootin'.
该死的。
Hey, barnacle brains, I think
you owe Plankton an apology.
嘿，藤壶脑，我想
你欠浮游生物一个道歉。
You're right, Plankton,
I'm sorry.
你说得对，浮游生物，
对不起。
Sorry you have to hang
out with rag boy.
抱歉你必须挂了
和破布男孩出去了。
All:
全部：
yeah, where'd you do your
clothes shopping, the trash can?
是的，你在哪里做你的
买衣服、扔垃圾桶？
All:
全部：
Mr. Krabs: 'Twas true, I did get
me clothes from the trash.
蟹老板：“这是真的，我确实得到了
我的衣服是从垃圾桶里捡来的。
You see, when I was growing up,
times were tough.
你看，在我成长的过程中，
日子很艰难。
Me mother had to fashion me
clothes from rags.
我妈妈必须塑造我
破布做的衣服。
There you go, Son, you're
outfit's all finished.
就这样吧，儿子，你就是
服装全部完成了
It's a good thing old man
Jenkins was kind enough to spare
his last washcloth.
老头真是好事
詹金斯很友善地饶恕了
他的最后一块毛巾。
Oops...
哎呀...
I missed a spot.
我错过了一个地方。
Mr. Krabs: Then one day
while Plankton and I plotted
our revenge
蟹老板：然后有一天
当浮游生物和我密谋时
我们的复仇
I met the love of me life.
我遇到了我一生的挚爱。
What in Neptune's net is that?
海王星的网里是什么？
It's the most beautiful thing me
eyes have ever seen.
这是我最美的事
眼睛曾经见过。
What is it?
它是什么？
It's money.
这是钱。
Money?
钱？
Yeah, you can buy things
with it.
是啊，可以买东西
与它。
Buy things?
买东西？
So I spent it on a gift for me
best pal, Plankton.
所以我把它花在了给我的礼物上
最好的朋友，浮游生物。
Ah...!
啊...！
All: Wow...
全体：哇……
Got your secret recipe,
Mr. Krabs.
得到了你的秘方，
蟹老板。
You have no idea what that went
through to get here.
你不知道发生了什么
通过到达这里。
I've got a pretty good idea.
我有一个很好的主意。
So if you guys were such great
friends, what happened?
所以如果你们都这么棒的话
朋友们，发生什么事了？
Yeah, Mr. Krabs,
what did happen next?
是的，蟹老板先生，
接下来发生了什么？
Yeah, I really wanna know.
是的，我真的很想知道。
Listen up, Squidward, 'cause
this is where it gets juicy.
听着，章鱼哥，因为
这就是它变得多汁的地方。
It all began in
a place called...
这一切都开始于
一个叫...的地方
Stinky Burgers.
臭汉堡。
It was the only place
to get a burger.
这是唯一的地方
去买一个汉堡。
The kids loved Stinky.
孩子们很喜欢臭臭。
All: Stinky, Stinky...!
全体：臭臭臭……！
Mr. Krabs: And Stinky
loved the kids.
蟹老板：还有臭味
喜欢孩子们。
What can I do
for you, young'uns?
我能做什么
对于你来说，年轻人？
Mr. Stinky, I'll have
one burger please.
臭先生，我会的
请来一个汉堡。
Me too, Stinky.
我也是，臭臭。
Now, now, kids, there's plenty
of burgers for everyone.
现在，现在，孩子们，有很多
适合每个人的汉堡。
That's why we like you so much,
Stinky, you always deliver
the goods.
这就是为什么我们如此喜欢你
臭臭的，你总是送东西
货物。
We don't like Stinky,
we respect him.
我们不喜欢臭味，
我们尊重他。
Well, which one is it, kids?
那么，孩子们，这是哪一个呢？
Do you like or respect me?
你喜欢我还是尊重我？
Like.
喜欢。
Respect.
尊重。
Like!
喜欢！
Respect!
尊重！
O.K., let's just meet in the
middle and say you li-spect me.
好吧，我们就在
中间并说你尊重我。
Mr. Krabs: Excuse us.
蟹老板：对不起。
Plankton: Valuable customers
coming through.
Plankton：有价值的客户
通过。
What are those dorks doing here?
那些呆子在这里做什么？
Two stinky burgers, please.
请给我两个臭汉堡。
Did your brains dribble out
onto the sidewalk you slept
on last night?
你的脑子有没有流出来
到你睡过的人行道上
昨晚？
If it's burgers you want,
go around back.
如果你想要汉堡
绕回去。
Kids: Yeah, stinky!
孩子们：是啊，臭！
Thanks for keeping
the nerds out.
感谢您的保留
书呆子们出去了。
You're the best, Stinky.
你是最棒的，臭臭。
O.K., that's enough, kids.
好吧，够了，孩子们。
Gather 'round, children.
聚集起来，孩子们。
There's something
I wanna tell you.
有东西
我想告诉你。
What I have to say
is very important.
我要说的话
非常重要。
If you remember just one thing
for the rest of your life,
remember that...
如果你只记得一件事
在你的余生中，
请记住...
Without your kind patronage,
I'd be a penniless loser
like rag boy.
没有您的善意惠顾，
我会是一个身无分文的失败者
就像破布男孩一样。
do you two have kelp for brains?
你们两个脑子里有海带吗？
Don't you understand?
你不明白吗？
If you two yahoos keep coming
around, you'll drive away all
the normal customers.
如果你们两个雅虎继续来
周围，你会赶走一切
普通顾客。
I've worked too long and
too hard to make this a
li-spectable business.
我已经工作了太久并且
太难了
值得尊敬的生意。
As it is, I can barely afford
the essential things in life.
事实上，我几乎买不起
生活中必不可少的东西。
is it quitting time already?
已经到下班时间了吗？
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'm off to enjoy some of
life's essentials.
现在请原谅我
我要去享受一些
生活必需品。
Ooh...!
噢...！
Did you hear that, Krabs?
你听到了吗，蟹蟹？
By cooking burgers for those
cretins, he was able to gain
their li-spect.
通过为那些人烹饪汉堡
白痴，他能够获得
他们的观点。
Did you see that fat
stack of loot?
你看到那个胖子了吗
一堆战利品？
I bet if someone made a better
burger, they'd have a fatter
stack of loot.
我打赌如果有人做得更好
汉堡，他们会更胖
一堆战利品。
But who has the ability
to make such a burger?
但谁有能力
做这样的汉堡？
Who has the skill?
谁有这个技能？
Skill Schmill, Krabs baby.
技能施米尔，蟹宝宝。
Who needs skill when science is
on your side?
当科学盛行时谁需要技能
在你这边吗？
Plankton: We'll make that
burger, and when we do
浮游生物：我们会做到的
汉堡，当我们这样做时
we will rule the school!
我们将统治学校！
: I miss Potty.
: 我想念波蒂。
I remember
the first time we met.
我记得
我们第一次见面。
If I could only hear his voice.
如果我能听到他的声音就好了。
Less talking and
more working, Jack.
少说话和
更多工作，杰克。
Potty?
便壶？
You came back to apologize.
你回来道歉了。
I came to tell you
to get back to work.
我是来告诉你的
回去工作。
You can't tell me
what to do, you...
你不能告诉我
该怎么办，你...
Patchy: Assistant manager?
帕奇：助理经理？
How did you get to be
assistant manager?
你是怎么变成这样的
经理助理？
A little thing called
a G.E.D., my man.
有一个小东西叫
一个 G.E.D.，我的朋友。
Oh, here we go with the
fancy book learning.
哦，我们来吧
奇特的书本学习。
Customers love me cooking.
顾客喜欢我做饭。
Why, we're almost out
of doggy bags.
为什么，我们快要出去了
的狗袋。
oh, Potty, what am I
doing wrong?
哦，Potty，我是什么？
做错了吗？
You just need some
practice is all.
你只需要一些
练习就是全部。
Ooh, me patty's done.
哦，我的帕蒂已经完成了。
Smells like an unswabbed
poop deck.
闻起来像未擦拭过的
船尾甲板。
Oh, fine, I'll try it then.
哦，好吧，那我就试试吧。
Ah...!
啊...！
For the crime of befouling me
taste buds, I order you to...
犯了污蔑我的罪
味蕾，我命令你……
Walk the plank!
走木板！
Ah...
啊...
Oh, well, I bet SpongeBob's
first Patty didn't go
so well either.
哦，好吧，我打赌海绵宝宝
首先帕蒂没有去
也很好。
Roll film.
胶卷。
A perfect Patty
on the first try.
完美的帕蒂
第一次尝试。
Oh...
哦...
I'll make a potty
Patty out of you.
我会做一个便盆
帕蒂离开你。
You're unsanitary, Patchy.
你不讲卫生，帕奇。
You keep hamburger
meat in an old boot.
你留着汉堡
旧靴子里的肉。
Well, that's what gives
it it's special flavor.
好吧，这就是给
它的味道很特别。
Potty: You've got rats
in the kitchen.
便盆：你有老鼠
在厨房里。
Oh, I brush and
shampoo them daily.
哦，我刷了
每天给他们洗头。
Who's Patchy's little Princess?
帕奇的小公主是谁？
Ow!
噢！
Oh, mmm...
哦，嗯……
Don't do that.
不要那样做。
And you should wash your hands
after using the bathroom.
你应该洗手
使用浴室后。
What?
什么？
Every time?
每次？
That's not all.
这还不是全部。
This is a step in
the right direction.
这是一个步骤
正确的方向。
What kind of a pirate
wears a hairnet?
什么样的海盗
戴发网吗？
The same kind that wears a "kiss
the cook" apron.
戴“吻”的同款
厨师”围裙。
Well, you never know, Potty,
I might get lucky.
好吧，你永远不知道，Potty，
我可能会幸运。
You hear that, ladies,
Patchy is available.
你们听到了，女士们，
补丁可用。
Now I feel sick.
现在我感觉不舒服。
That's it, you feathered snake.
就是这样，你这只长着羽毛的蛇。
This time you've gone too far.
这次你太过分了。
Patty: You missed.
帕蒂：你错过了。
is that all you've got?
这就是你所拥有的一切吗？
Now you've done it.
现在你已经做到了。
Argh...
啊啊……
Yes, Mr. Pirateson.
是的，海盗先生。
You kids watch the rest of
the cartoon, while I watch
Potty get fired.
你们孩子们看剩下的
当我看漫画的时候
波蒂被解雇了。
Mr. Pirateson: Argh...
海盗先生：啊……
Coming, Mr. Pirateson, sir.
来了，海盗先生，先生。
Mr. Krabs: So we went back to
our secret hideaway...
蟹老板：所以我们回到了
我们的秘密藏身处...
The dump.
垃圾场。
To prove to those chowder heads
that a burger could be
semi-edible
向那些杂烩头证明
汉堡可以是
半食用的
and easy to swallow.
且易于吞咽。
We made sure to keep careful
record of our progress.
我们一定要小心
记录我们的进步。
Plankton: Gently.
浮游生物：轻轻地。
Gently.
轻轻地。
Mr. Krabs: We finally emerged
with the best-looking
burger under the sea.
蟹老板：我们终于出现了
与最好看的
汉堡在海底。
We went back to Stinky's
to rub our Patty in those
kids' greasy faces.
我们又回到了臭臭店
把我们的帕蒂擦在那些身上
孩子们油腻的脸。
But Stinky's had been
shut down by order of
the health department.
但臭臭的已经
按以下命令关闭
卫生部门。
So we seized the opportunity,
and converted our hangout
to a restaurant.
于是我们抓住了这个机会，
并转换了我们的环聊
到一家餐馆。
Pur venture into
capitalism began.
追求冒险
资本主义开始了。
$1, please.
1 美元，请。
There you are, sir.
就在这儿，先生。
Mr. Krabs: 'Twas me first
dollar I'd ever earned.
蟹老板：“首先是我
我赚过的美元。
And 'twas also the beginning
of a beautiful romantic
relationship with money.
这也是开始
一个美丽浪漫的
与金钱的关系。
Kid: Hey...
孩子：嘿……
You're burgers are even
worse than Stinky's.
你的汉堡很均匀
比臭臭的还要糟糕。
We can barely keep 'em down.
我们几乎无法阻止他们。
If it weren't for Stinky's
shuttin' down, no one
would eat here.
如果不是臭臭
关门了，没有人
会在这里吃饭。
Now give me a burger.
现在给我一个汉堡。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
Just look at them, Eugene.
看看他们，尤金。
Plankton: The very people who
ridiculed me are now feasting
on my recipe.
浮游生物：正是那些
嘲笑我现在正在吃喝玩乐
在我的食谱上。
I thought it was our recipe.
我以为这是我们的食谱。
I'm ruling their stomachs.
我在统治他们的胃。
And soon, I will be
ruling their minds.
很快，我就会
统治他们的思想。
But what about satisfying
the customer?
但满足又怎样
客户？
Barnacles to the customer.
藤壶给顾客。
I'm talking about
ruling the world!
我说的是
统治世界！
And with this secret recipe,
nothing will stop me.
有了这个秘方，
没有什么能阻止我。
Give me that.
给我那个。
Stop, you're gonna bust it.
停下来，你会毁了它。
Burgers aren't for
ruling worlds.
汉堡不适合
统治世界。
I'm terribly sorry, Eugene,
I couldn't hear you.
我非常抱歉 尤金
我听不见你说话。
Could you come closer?
你能靠近点吗？
Maybe stand on the tile
in front of you.
也许站在瓷砖上
在你面前。
Which one?
哪一个？
The one that says "eject"
那个写着“弹出”的
or the one that says
"trap door"?
或者那个说
“活板门”？
Oh, either one will do.
哦，任何一个都可以。
What I was saying was...
我想说的是...
You'll regret this one day.
有一天你会后悔的。
And he always did.
他总是这样做。
Lies!
谎言！
Hold on there, me boy.
坚持住，我的孩子。
We don't need to go
through all that again.
我们不需要去
再次经历这一切。
Very touching,
but completely false.
非常感人，
但完全错误。
Don't know what you mean.
不知道你的意思。
Why don't you tell
them the truth?
你为什么不告诉
他们说的是实话吗？
It  did  happen that way
didn't it Mr. Krabs?
事情确实是这样发生的
不是蟹老板吗？
Most of it is true, except for
what  really  happened.
大部分都是真的，除了
到底发生了什么。
We had created
the tastiest burger.
我们创造了
最美味的汉堡。
That's when things
became unsavory.
这时候事情
变得令人厌恶。
First, we rule their
stomachs, and then...
首先，我们统治他们
肚子，然后……
their money.
他们的钱。
But what about satisfying
the customers?
但满足又怎样
客户？
Barnacles to the customers.
藤壶给顾客。
I'm talking about coins, cash,
wallets, bank accounts.
我说的是硬币、现金
钱包、银行账户。
And with this secret recipe,
nothing will stop me!
有了这个秘方，
没有什么能阻止我！
Give me that.
给我那个。
Stop, you're gonna bust it.
停下来，你会毁了它。
This isn't about money, Eugene.
这不是钱的问题，尤金。
Malarkey.
说大话。
You'll regret this one day!
有一天你会后悔的！
Ouch.
哎哟。
Huh?
啊？
Our little squabble only got me
part of the recipe.
我们的小争吵只伤害了我
食谱的一部分。
SpongeBob: Gosh, Mr. Plankton
海绵宝宝：天啊，浮游生物先生
That doesn't sound like the
Mr. Krabs story at all.
这听起来不像
蟹老板的故事根本就没有。
Voice: That's because it isn't.
声音：那是因为事实并非如此。
All: Karen?
全体：凯伦？
Karen: You're both liars.
凯伦：你们都是骗子。
That's not how it
happened at all.
事情不是这样的
发生了。
In those days, I was just
starting out as a
security system.
那些日子里，我只是
开始作为
安全系统。
Plankton and I met when he
installed me.
Plankton 和我是在他认识的时候认识的
安装了我。
It was only our third date.
这只是我们的第三次约会。
Karen: Anyways, I recorded the
whole thing in my databanks.
凯伦：不管怎样，我录了
整个事情都在我的数据库中。
Now that's a handsome
looking burger.
现在是个帅哥
寻找汉堡。
You said it, old chum.
你说的是吧，老朋友。
Mr. Krabs: Attention,
get your Plankton and
Krabs Patties right here.
蟹老板：注意，
得到你的浮游生物和
蟹肉饼就在这里。
You think it was a good
idea to open a in a dump?
你认为这是一个好的
想在垃圾场开一个吗？
What's that music?
那是什么音乐？
I'd know that theme
song anywhere.
我就知道这个主题
任何地方的歌曲。
It's old man Jenkins.
这是老詹金斯。
Mr. Krabs: Old man Jenkins?
蟹老板：老詹金斯？
I've just been searching for
some new shoes for old Bessie.
我刚刚一直在寻找
给老贝西一些新鞋。
You helped me mom and me
through some tough times.
你帮助了我妈妈和我
度过一些艰难的时期。
It would be an honor if you'd
be the first to try our
delicious burgers.
如果您愿意，那将是我的荣幸
成为第一个尝试我们的
美味的汉堡。
Why, I'd be happy to.
为什么，我很乐意。
Yeah!
是的！
Mr. Krabs: "Plab Patty's
K.O. Old Man J."
蟹老板：“Plab Patty’s
K.O. J老头。”
I can't believe we poisoned
that sweet old guy.
我不敢相信我们中毒了
那个可爱的老家伙。
Well, he is old.
嗯，他老了。
Hey, that guy's like
family to me.
嘿，那家伙就像
家人对我来说。
Well, it was your fault
the patty was tainted.
好吧，这是你的错
肉饼被污染了。
You're the one who put too much
seaweed sauce in the burger.
你是那个投入太多的人
汉堡里的海藻酱。
You let it sit out too long.
你让它放置太久了。
That's what did it.
就是这么做的。
I'm taking the recipe
and fixing it.
我拿着菜谱
并修复它。
No way, that recipe's mine.
不可能，那个食谱是我的。
Stop, you're gonna...
停下来，你会...
You wanna fight over this
recipe, I'll give you a fight
you'll never forget.
你想为此而战
菜谱，我要给你打架
你永远不会忘记。
Well, that's ruined.
嗯，那就毁了。
But no use letting
this go to waste.
但让也没有用
这就浪费了。
These kids'll eat anything.
这些孩子什么都吃。
I've done it.
我已经做到了。
I've discovered the
perfect patty batter.
我发现了
完美的肉饼面糊。
Karen: Meanwhile, Plankton was
back at the elementary school.
凯伦：与此同时，浮游生物
回到小学。
But this time he was
going it alone.
但这一次他是
独自前行。
Oh, no you don't.
哦，不，你不知道。
This is my turf.
这是我的地盘。
I think not, rag boy.
我想不是，破布男孩。
What?
什么？
Why I ought to squash you
right now, you little...
为什么我应该压扁你
现在，你这个小...
Get out of my face.
从我面前滚出去。
Both:
两个都：
Hey, look, nerd fight.
嘿，看，书呆子打架。
I got $5 on rag boy.
我在 rag boy 上得到了 5 美元。
Ah-hah!
啊哈！
We'll let the customers decide
who's burger's better.
我们会让客户决定
谁的汉堡更好。
Step right up, gents.
先生们，请站起来。
Get a delicious Chum Burger
right here.
获得美味的 Chum 汉堡
就在这里。
Big Johnny will eat anything.
大约翰尼什么都吃。
Have a Chum Burger, Johnny sir.
约翰尼先生，来一份密姆汉堡吧。
Karen: Plankton had pieced
together his own creation using
memory and science.
凯伦：浮游生物已经拼凑起来
结合他自己的创作
记忆和科学。
Go on, sir, tell your buddies
what you think.
先生，快去告诉你的朋友吧
你怎么想。
I'm gonna try one of
rag boy's burgers.
我要尝试其中之一
破布男孩的汉堡。
Here you are, sir.
在这里，先生。
You are the first to taste
Krabby Patty.
你是第一个品尝的
克拉比·帕蒂。
Flavor!
味道！
Edible!
食用！
We can actually hold it down.
其实我们可以把它压住。
This is the most
"flavortastic" sensation
这是最
“美味”的感觉
my still-developing taste buds
have ever experienced!
我仍在发育的味蕾
曾经经历过！
I'll show you, Krabs.
我会告诉你，蟹蟹。
I'll steal that cursed recipe
from you one day.
我会偷走那个被诅咒的食谱
有一天从你那里。
And I won't stop till I do.
在我这样做之前我不会停止。
Whoo hoo!
呼呼！
Ha!
哈!
My recipe was...
我的食谱是...
is...
是...
and always will be the best.
并且永远是最好的。
You wouldn't have that
recipe if it weren't for me!
你不会有那个
如果不是我的菜谱！
You calling me a liar?
你骂我是骗子？
Karen: Will you men stop
yelling at each other?
凯伦：你们能停下来吗
互相大喊大叫？
I can't believe you let
a recipe ruin such a
wonderful friendship.
我不敢相信你让
一个食谱毁了这样一个
美好的友谊。
You were my only true friend
that didn't have a president
printed on him.
你是我唯一真正的朋友
没有总统
印在他身上。
But money doesn't talk back.
但钱是不会反驳的。
My life has been nothing but a
long line of disappointment
since we became enemies.
我的生活只不过是
排长队失望
自从我们成为敌人。
All these years, I've been
trying to steal your formula.
这些年来，我一直
试图窃取你的配方。
But I was really just trying to
steal back our friendship.
但我真的只是想
偷回我们的友谊。
Really?
真的吗？
It's all I ever really
wanted, to get back to
the way it used to be.
这就是我曾经真正的一切
想要回到
就像以前那样。
You and me against the world.
你我对抗世界。
How about a hug, Krabs, old pal?
蟹蟹老朋友，拥抱一下怎么样？
I'd like that, Planky, old chum.
我想要这个，普朗基，老朋友。
Doesn't this warm
your heart, Karen?
这不暖和吗
你的心，凯伦？
Karen: I suppose it would,
if I had one.
凯伦：我想会的，
如果我有的话。
I'm sorry, Krabs old buddy.
对不起，蟹蟹老伙计。
Mr. Krabs: Me too, me too...
蟹老板：我也是，我也是……
Now, Karen.
现在，凯伦。
Back off, rag boy.
退后吧，破布男孩。
sabotage!
破坏！
Go, Karen.
走吧，凯伦。
Oh, that Plankton never learns,
does he, kids?
哦，浮游生物永远不会学习，
孩子们，他是吗？
As for me, I decided
to take some time off
to catch up on me reading.
至于我，我决定
休息一段时间
赶上我的阅读进度。
You didn't take time off.
你没有请假。
You got fired.
你被解雇了。
Hey, you got fired, too.
嘿，你也被解雇了。
I got a golden parachute.
我有一个金色的降落伞。
Well, at least I know they'll
never be able to replace me.
好吧，至少我知道他们会
永远无法取代我。
looks like
they already did.
看起来像
他们已经这么做了。
What?
什么？
They let a smelly, hairy,
fleabag like that serve food?
他们让臭气熏天、毛茸茸的、
像这样的跳蚤提供食物吗？
Hey, watch it, ape!
嘿，小心点，猿！
Ooh, ow, ow....
噢噢噢……
Watch the patch!
看补丁！
Ow, no, please...
噢，不，请...
I have a tomato allergy.
我对番茄过敏。
Ow!
噢！
Right in the buns.
就在面包里。
Ow, ooh, ow!
噢，噢，噢！
Man: And so, kids, always
remember to follow your dreams,
unless you're Patchy.
男人：所以，孩子们，永远
记得追随你的梦想，
除非你是帕奇。
Then just stay in bed.
然后就躺在床上吧。